
questions_list = [
        {
            "question": "Does C programming requires indentation?",
            "options": ["Yes", "No", "Sometimes it requires and sometimes it doesn't.", "None of the above "],
            "correct_answer": "No"
        },
        {
            "question": "What do you mean by algorithm?",
            "options": ["Any complex code to solve a problem. ", "Pictorial representation of steps required to solve a problem ", " A set of rules or instructions required to solve a problem.", "Both B and C. "],
            "correct_answer": " A set of rules or instructions required to solve a problem."
        },
        {
            "question": '''Choose the correct option:
            1.int[4]={10,20,30,40}
    2.int[]={10,20,30,40}
    3.int[];
    4.int[4]={10,20}''',
            "options": ["1,2", "1,2,3", "1,3,4", "1,2,4"],
            "correct_answer": "1,2,4"
        },
        {
            "question": "let A = 3 and B = 6 . Then printf((A++)-(2%(- -B))) will be equal to ______?",
            "options": ["2", "3", "0", "1"],
            "correct_answer": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": '''Find the output of the following code -
                int main(){
                printf(" hello world ")
                int a = 5;
                while (int i = 2; i<= a; i++){
                    printf(" hello world ");
                    a += 2;
                    a += 2;
                }
    How many times does " hello world " will print?''',
            "options": ["4", "6", "5", "3"],
            "correct_answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the phenomenon that describes the bending of light around obstacles and spreading out as it passes through narrow openings?",
            "options": ["Reflection", "Refraction", "Diffraction", "Interference"],
            "correct_answer": "Diffraction"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two identical small conducting spheres, A and B, carry charges of +2.1 μC and -4.5 μC, respectively. They are brought into contact and then separated. What is the final charge on sphere A? ",
            "options": ["-1.2 μC", "-2.4 μC", "+1.2 μC", "+2.4 μC"],
            "correct_answer": "-1.2 μC"
        },
        {
            "question": "A long straight wire carries a current \(I_1\). A small circular loop is placed parallel to the wire and current \(I_2\) is induced in the loop due to the changing magnetic flux. If the loop is pulled away from the wire with a constant velocity, what will happen to the magnitude and direction of the induced current \(I_2\)?",
            "options": ["The magnitude of i2 increases and its direction remains the same.", "The magnitude of i2 increases and its direction reverses.", "The magnitude of i2 decreases and its direction remains the same.", "The magnitude of i2 decreases and its direction reverses."],
            "correct_answer": "The magnitude of i2 decreases and its direction remains the same. "
        },
        {
            "question": "Which logic gate performs the operation of complement? ",
            "options": ["AND Gate", "OR Gate", "XOR Gate", "NAND Gate"],
            "correct_answer": "NAND Gate"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the decimal equivalent of the binary number 10101?",
            "options": ["15", "17", "20", "21"],
            "correct_answer": "21"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which regions BJT acts as a amplifier and a switch 'on' condition respectively?",
            "options": ["active, cutoff", "active, saturation", "cutoff, saturation", "cutoff, active"],
            "correct_answer": "active, saturation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the correct expression of efficiency of half wave rectifier?",
            "options": ["2", "3", "0", "1"],
            "correct_answer": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Given Rf=3kohm, Ri=10 ohm what will be the Vout in case of a non inverting op amp when Vin=5mv.",
            "options": ["1.505V", "6V", "3V", "4V"],
            "correct_answer": "1.505V"
        },
        {
            "question": "what is equivalent of ABC+AB'C'D+AB'C'D'?",
            "options": ["A (B XNOR C)", " A (B XNOR C)", "A'BC'", "A XOR B XOR C"],
            "correct_answer": "A (B XNOR C)"
        },
        {
            "question": " A=No. of Analog pins in Arduino nano\nB=No. of digital pins in Arduino nano\nWhat will be the value of 2A-B.",
            "options": ["Windows 95", "Xenix", "MS-DOS", "GMOS"],
            "correct_answer": "MS-DOS"
        },

        {
            "question": "Which Indian state recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the company 'SRAM & MRAM' to establish a semiconductor manufacturing unit, aiming to bolster its electronics manufacturing sector? ",
            "options": ["Karnataka", "Odisha", "Tamil Nadu", "Maharashtra"],
            "correct_answer": "Odisha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the full form of XPoSat? What is the objective of the satellite?",
            "options": [" POLIX SPRECTROSCOPY satellite, carry out research to study on black holes ", "XSpect Satellite, to carry out research on the radio wave signals generated from celestial sources ", "X-ray Polarimeter Satellite, carry out research in space-based polarisation measurements of X-ray emission from celestial sources ", " X ray Polix satellite, carry out further research of the corona layer of Sun "],
            "correct_answer": "X-ray Polarimeter Satellite, carry out research in space-based polarisation measurements of X-ray emission from celestial sources"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which institution recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Marquee Semiconductor to collaborate on research and development projects in the field of semiconductor technology? ",
            "options": ["IIT Bombay ", "VSSUT Burla", "BITS Pilani", "NIT Trichy"],
            "correct_answer": "VSSUT Burla"
        },{
            "question": """US-based multi-national company "X" opened its new centre in Bhubaneshwar Odisha . X has a revenue over 20 billion USD , it is a part of NASDAQ-100 and employs more than 350,000 professionals worldwide . Name the company X.""",
            "options": ["Cognizant", "Intel", "Samsung ", "AMD "],
            "correct_answer": "Cognizant"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which of the following is NOT considered one of the four functions of management?  ",
            "options": ["Planning", "Organizing", "Evaluating", "Leading"],
            "correct_answer": "Evaluating"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which management theorist is known for introducing the concept of scientific management?",
            "options": ["Frederick Taylor", "Henri Fayol", " Max Weber", "Elton Mayo"],
            "correct_answer": "Frederick Taylor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which leadership style encourages team members to participate in decision-making and problem-solving processes?",
            "options": ["Autocratic", "Transformational", "Servant", "Charismatic"],
            "correct_answer": "Transformational"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you have 15 chocolates, and in every exchange of 3 chocolates you will get a chocolate & ₹1 for free then what will be your total earning at the end. ",
            "options": ["₹8", "₹7", "₹5", "₹9"],
            "correct_answer": "₹7"
        },
        {
            "question": " Arrange the words in a meaningful sequence.\n(a) Execution \n (b) Investment \n(C) Idea \n(d) Revenue \n(e) Planning",

            "options": ["d, e, b, c, a", "c, e, b, a, d", "c, b, d, a, e", "c, e, a, b, d"],
            "correct_answer": "c, e, b, a, d"
        },
        {
            "question": "AMB, CLB, BKC, DJC, ______ ",
            "options": ["EID ", "CJD ", "EIF", "CID"],
            "correct_answer": "CID"
        },
        {
            "question": " Statement: French language learning should be started in school. \n Assumptions:   (i) French language is easy to learn \n (ii) Learning French helps in getting a job ",
            "options": [" Assumption I is implied  ", "Assumption II is implied", "Either I or II is implied ", "Neither I or II is implied "],
            "correct_answer": " Assumption I is implied "
        },
        {
            "question": "Arrange the words below in their appropriate sequence. \n 5.Morning 3.facewash 1.brush 2.Take bath 4.Exercise ",
            "options": ["5, 1, 2, 4, 3 ", "5, 3, 4, 1, 2 ", "5, 3, 1, 4, 2 ", "1, 2, 3, 5, 4 "],
            "correct_answer": "5, 3, 1, 4, 2"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a certain language, BOOK is written as 4300, MATE is written as 3900. Then 2800 will represent which word out of given alternatives? ",
            "options": ["READ ", "WOOD ", "CRAB", "CAKE "],
            "correct_answer": "READ"
        },
        {
            "question": " The angle formed by the hour and minute hands at 8:20 ?",
            "options": ["110o", "130o", "150o", "140o"],
            "correct_answer": "130o"
        },
        {
            "question": " If the price of a laptop is increased by 15% and the new price is ₹30,000, what was the original price? ",
            "options": [" ₹25,000 ", " ₹26,000", "₹26,500", "₹27,000"],
            "correct_answer": "₹26,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sum of ages of a father and his son is 48 years. Four years ago, the father was four times as old as his son. Find their present ages. ",
            "options": [" Father: 36 years, Son: 12 years ", " Father: 40 years, Son: 8 years ", "Father: 44 years, Son: 4 years", "Father: 32 years, Son: 16 years "],
            "correct_answer": "Father: 40 years, Son: 8 years "
        },
        {
            "question": "A man and a woman working together can complete a job in 10 days. If the man works at twice his speed and the woman at half her speed, the job would take 6 days. How many days would it take for the man alone to complete the job? ",
            "options": [" 15 days", " 20 days", " 25 days", "30 days"],
            "correct_answer": " 25 days"
        },
        {
            "question": " A cylindrical tank has a diameter of 14 meters and is filled with water up to a height of 10 meters. If 4 cubic meters of water is drained out, what is the new height of the water level? ",
            "options": [" 8 meters ", " 8.5 meters", "9 meters", " 9.5 meters "],
            "correct_answer": "9.5 meters"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sum of ages of a father and his son is 48 years. Four years ago, the father was four times as old as his son. Find their present ages.",
            "options": [" Father: 36 years, Son: 12 years", " Father: 40 years, Son: 8 years", " Father: 44 years, Son: 4 years", " Father: 32 years, Son: 16 years"],
            "correct_answer": "Father: 40 years, Son: 8 years"
        }

    ]

